
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">StoryProject</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->

    <string name="Heading">The  Lion and the Man</string>
    <string name="play"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="stop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="content"> A Lion and a Man chanced to travel in a company through the forest.They soon began to quarrel, for each of them boasted that he and his kind were far superior to the other both in strength and mind.

Now they reached a clearing in the forest and there stood a statue. It was a representation of Heracles in the act of tearing the jaws of the Nemean Lion.


“See,” said the man, “that’s how strong we are! The King of Beasts is like wax in our hands!”



“Ho!” laughed the Lion, “a Man made that statue. It would have been quite a different scene had a Lion made it!”



        Moral: It all depends on the point of view, and who tells the story. Always trust your own wit and try judge the circumstances.
        </string>
    <string name="pig">The Pig and the Sheep</string>
    <string name="pigplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="pigstop"> ⏹️</string>

    <string name="pigcontent">
        One day a shepherd discovered a fat Pig in the meadow where his Sheep were pastured. He very quickly captured the porker, which squealed at the top of its voice the moment the Shepherd laid his hands on it. You would have thought, to hear the loud squealing, that the Pig was being cruelly hurt. But in spite of its squeals and struggles to escape, the Shepherd tucked his prize under his arm and started off to the butcher’s in the marketplace.

The Sheep in the pasture were much astonished and amused at the Pig’s behavior and followed the Shepherd and his charge to the pasture gate.

“What makes you squeal like that?” asked one of the Sheep. “The Shepherd often catches and carries off one of us. But we should feel very much ashamed to make such a terrible fuss about it like you do.”



“That is all very well,” replied the Pig, with a squeal and a frantic kick. “When he catches you he is only after your wool. But he wants my bacon! gree-ee-ee!”

Moral: It is easy to be brave when there is no danger. Don’t compare two different situations without understanding them.</string>
    <string name="wolf">The sheperd and the wolf</string>
    <string name="wolfplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="wolfstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="wolfcontent"> A Shepherd Boy tended his master’s Sheep near a dark forest not far from the village. Soon he found life in the pasture very dull. All he could do to amuse himself was to talk to his dog or play on his shepherd’s pipe.

One day as he sat watching the Sheep and the quiet forest, and thinking what he would do should he see a Wolf, he thought of a plan to amuse himself. His Master had told him to call for help should a Wolf attack the flock, and the Villagers would drive it away. So now, though he had not seen anything that even looked like a Wolf, he ran toward the village shouting at the top of his voice, “Wolf! Wolf!”

As he expected, the Villagers who heard the cry dropped their work and ran in great excitement to the pasture. But when they got there they found the Boy doubled up with laughter at the trick he had played on them. A few days later the Shepherd Boy again shouted, “Wolf! Wolf!” Again the Villagers ran to help him, only to be laughed at again.



Then one evening as the sun was setting behind the forest and the shadows were creeping out over the pasture, a Wolf really did spring from the underbrush and fall upon the Sheep.

In terror the Boy ran toward the village shouting “Wolf! Wolf!” But though the Villagers heard the cry, they did not run to help him as they had before. “He cannot fool us again,” they said.

The Wolf killed a great many of the Boy’s sheep and then slipped away into the forest.

Moral: If you keep lying, no one will believe you even if you are speaking the truth. Always speak the truth</string>
    <string name="crane">The Wolf and the crane</string>
    <string name="craneplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="cranestop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="cranecontent"> A Wolf had been feasting too greedily, and a bone had stuck crosswise in his throat. He could get it neither up nor down, and of course, he could not eat a thing. Naturally, that was an awful state of affairs for a greedy Wolf.

So away he hurried to the Crane. He was sure that she, with her long neck and bill, would easily be able to reach the bone and pull it out. “I will reward you very handsomely”, said the Wolf, “if you pull that bone out for me”.

The Crane, as you can imagine, was very uneasy about putting her head in Wolf’s throat. But she was grasping in nature, so she did what the Wolf asked her to do. When the Wolf felt that the bone was gone, he started to walk away.



“But what about my reward!” called the Crane anxiously.

“What!” snarled the Wolf, whirling around. “Haven’t you got it? Isn’t it enough that I let you take your head out of my mouth without snapping it off?”

Moral: Expect no reward for serving the one who has no honor. Staying in a company of selfish people will not do anyone any favor.</string>
    <string name="wealth">Wealth without Value</string>
    <string name="wealthplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="wealthstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="wealthcontent">A Miser had buried his gold in a secret place in his garden. Every day he went to the spot, dug up the treasure and counted it piece by piece to make sure it was all there. He made so many trips that a Thief, who had been observing him, guessed what it was the Miser had hidden, and one night quietly dug up the treasure and made off with it.

When the Miser discovered his loss, he was overcome with grief and despair. He groaned and cried and tore his hair. A passerby heard his cries and asked what had happened.

“My gold! O my gold!” cried the Miser, wildly, “someone has robbed me!”



“Your gold! There in that hole? Why did you put it there? Why did you not keep it in the house where you could easily get it when you had to buy things?”

“Buy!” screamed the Miser angrily. “Why, I never touched the gold. I couldn’t think of spending any of it.”

The stranger picked up a large stone and threw it into the hole. “If that is the case,” he said, “cover up that stone. It is worth just as much to you as the treasure you lost!”

Moral: Saving, Spending wisely and appropriately is a good sign if you do it for a good purpose. Otherwise, a possession is worth no more than the use we make of it.</string>
    <string name="sun">Why the sun and the moon</string>
    <string name="sunplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="sunstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="suncontent">Many years ago, the sun and water were great friends, and they both lived on the earth togther. The sun very often used to visit the water, but the water never returned the visits.

At last the sun asked the water why he never visited. The water replied that the suns house was not big enough, and that if he came with all his people, he would drive the sun out of his home.

The water then said, If you want me to visit you, you will have to build a very large house. But I warn you that it will have to be very large, as my people are numerous and take up a lot of room.

The sun promised to build a very large house, and soon afterwards, he returned home to his wife, the moon, who greeted him with a broad smile.

The sun told the moon what he had promised the water, and the next day, they began building a large house to entertain the water and all his people.

When it was completed, the sun asked the water to come and visit him.

When the water arrived, one of his people called out to the sun, and asked him whether it would be safe for the water to enter, and the sun answered, Yes, tell my friend to come in.

The water began to flow in, followed by the fish and all the other water animals.

Very soon, the water was knee-deep in the house, so he asked the sun if it was still safe, and the sun again said, Yes, so more of them came in.

When the water was at the level of a mans head, the water said to the sun, Do you want more of my people to come

Not knowing any better, the sun and the moon both said, Yes,. More and more of the waters people came in, until the sun and the moon had to sit on top of the roof.

The water once again asked the sun if it was still okay to keep coming in. The sun and moon answered yes, so more and more of the waters people came in.

The water soon overflowed the top of the roof, and the sun and the moon were forced to go up into the sky.

‌…and they have been there ever since.
    </string>
    <string name="friend">The Two Friends</string>
    <string name="friendplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="friendstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="friendcontent">One upon a time there were two friends from childhood days named Harry and Peter. Both trusted each other and used to help each other whenever they needed. They grew up together and entered in their respective career. Out of them Harry was quite happy with his small earning but Peter was very greedy and always used to think how to make more wealth and was not happy with small earnings but it did not affect true friendship between them.

Peter came across with one elderly person Jack who told him that he can help him to earn more money, provided he follows him in his way of work. Peter agreed to do whatever Jack wanted him to do. Jack was a criminal and he ultimately involved Peter with him for cheating person through their ATM withdrawal by doing skimming activity. Gradually Peter could earn lots of money and become a rich person.

His childhood friend Harry could realize that Peter must be doing some unlawful job for earning money and become a rich person. Understanding this he started avoiding Peter and ultimately a distance between the two friends happened. Peter earned lots of money and started his own number of business to become wealthier person. About 10 years have passed the two friends were detached from themselves but no body forgets each other from their heart. Suddenly Peter needed a trusted person to look after his business and help him in earning more money. He remembers his old friend Harry and started searching him and his whereabouts. After a long search he came to know that Harry is very much sick and hospitalized and needs lots of money for his surgery. Peter knew that if he gives money to Harry he will not take it. As he has earned the money in dishonest way. But still he wanted to help him and pay all the hospital charges amounting six lakhs with the pretext that the money has come from a charity fund. When Harry recovered from his illness and inquired how the money has come he understands that it is his childhood friend Peter who arranged the money. Harry became angry and met Peter and asked him why he paid his money. Peter simply replied “A friend in need is a friend indeed”.</string>
    <string name="miser">The King and The Beggar</string>
    <string name="miserplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="miserstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="misercontent">

Once upon a time a country was ruled by a king who had no son to succeed to the throne.

Since the king was getting old he wanted to select a suitable successor to rule the country.

The king sent out notices throughout his country.

The notice has invited every qualified young man in the country for an interview with the king.

The outcome of the interview would decide a possible successor to the throne.

The only qualification for the candidate was that they should have immense love for their fellow human beings.

Every young man across the country was very excited at the possibility of being the ruler of the country.

A poor young man from a remote Village also read the notice and started to prepare for an interview with the king.

The man was a kind and hard-working man but he was very poor due to various circumstances.

The man had no good clothes to be presentable in the sight of the king.

So the young man worked really hard and saved some money to buy him proper clothes and supplies to support him for the long journey to the palace.

After he got his supplies and a proper attire for the interview the young man set out on his quest.

He traveled many days and had almost completed the journey.

When he came upon a poor beggar by the side of the road, the poor beggar said trembling in the cold covered only in tattered rags.

The beggar extended his arms and pleaded for help.

His weak voice croaked “I am hungry and cold please help me sir”.

The young man was so moved by the pathetic condition of the beggar that he immediately stripped his new attire and offered it to him.

He also provided him with his very limited food he had carried for the journey.

The beggar thanked the man a thousand times but since the man had given up his good clothes to the beggar, he was a bit hesitant to go for the interview.

He however gathered enough courage to enter the palace in his old-dirty clothes.

Upon his arrival at the palace, the King’s attendant showed him the way to the Great Hall.

After a short rest to clean off the journey’s tiredness.

The man was admitted to the throne room for the interview.

The young man bowed low as the King entered the room. when he raised his eyes he gasped in astonishment as he noticed that the King looked very similar to the beggar he had met on the way.

The King saw the shock in the man’s eye and said “yes, I was the beggar you met on your way”

But why did you dress up like a beggar, you are a king!. well, why did you do this to me

The young man stammered after gaining some composure.

“Because, I had to be sure that you had a good heart and you genuinely loved your fellow human beings.” said the king.

I knew that if I came to you as a king you would have done anything to impress me but that way I would never have known what is truly in your heart.

The generosity and love to the one in need without expecting anything in return is the sign of a great heart.

Looking at your love and generosity towards the beggar man proved that you sincerely love your fellow human beings.

This country needs a leader who would work for the welfare of all of the nation not just the ones who would do anything to get the throne.

“You have proven that you are the right person to be my successor” promised the king.

Moral Of The Story:
You see in life kindness is more important than wisdom and the recognition of this is the beginning of wisdom.

A heart filled with compassion and love to our fellow human beings is the greatest gift we can give to the world.

A king in this land today might be rich and glamorous, might have the power and all the strength.

But this kingdom is worthless compared to a rich
heart of the young man.

The kindness and compassion of the young man towards the beggar made him the king of the entire nation.

We, As a human should help other fellow beings in need without expecting anything in return. </string>
    <string name="four">The Four Dragons</string>
    <string name="fourplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="fourstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="fourcontent">“The Four Dragons” is a tale from China where long ago, the story says, there were no lakes or rivers, only the Eastern Sea, home to four dragons: the Long Dragon, the Yellow Dragon, the Black Dragon, and the Pearl Dragon. These dragons swam in the sea and flew in the air above. One day, as they were playing in the clouds, the Pearl Dragon saw a disturbing sight he shared with the others. He saw the people down below praying for rain. The land was in a drought, the plants were withering, and the people had nothing to eat. The dragons realized that the people would die if it did not rain soon, so the Long Dragon suggested they visit the Jade Emperor, who was in charge of all the affairs in heaven and earth, and beg for rain. After they made their request the Jade Emperor agreed to send rain.

The dragons happily went back to their home, but the rain never came. After ten days, the dragons realized that the Jade Emperor didn’t truly care about the people and that it was up to them to provide rain. The Long Dragon came up with the idea of scooping water out of the Eastern Sea and spraying it towards the sky, where it would fall on the earth like rain. All the dragons agreed and followed through with the plan, even knowing that the Jade Emperor would be displeased when he found out.

The people were overjoyed when the rain fell, but the god of the sea reported the dragons’ behavior to the Jade Emperor who was furious. He had the four dragons arrested and imprisoned under four mountains. “The Dragons never regretted their decision and determined to continue to do good for the people, they turned themselves into four rivers, which flowed past the high mountains and deep valleys, crossing the land from the west to the east, and finally emptied into the sea. Thus they became China’s four great rivers-the Heilongjian (Black Dragon), the Huanghe (Yellow Dragon), the Changjiang (Long Dragon), and the Zhujiang (Pearl Dragon). ”

You can read the story on-line in several places, including here.

I especially enjoy creation myths, stories that helped people make sense of the world. In this story we have four higher beings giving up their freedom for the lives of the people. I don’t know much about Chinese culture, but dragons seem to be powerful, wise, strong. They are revered, not creatures to be slain as in European stories.

I have to admire the dragons. They saw a problem, saw how desperate the villagers were and became determined to help. They went through the official channels first, making their request to the Jade Emperor, but when that didn’t accomplish anything, they took matters into their own hands. People in charge are not always right, do not always have others’ best interests at heart. The dragons knew they were risking punishment, but they all agreed that it was worth the price and did what needed to be done. Even when they were imprisoned forever, they never regretted their decision and continued to do whatever they could to help the people.

</string>
    <string name="man">The man who never lied</string>
    <string name="manplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="manstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="mancontent">Once upon a time there lived a wise man by the name of Mamad. He never lied. All the people in the land, even the ones who lived twenty days away, knew about him.

The king heard about Mamad and ordered his subjects to bring him to the palace. He looked at the wise man and asked:

" Mamad, is it true, that you have never lied?"

" It's true."

"And you will never lie in your life?"

" I'm sure in that."

"Okay, tell the truth, but be careful! The lie is cunning and it gets on your tongue easily."

Several days passed and the king called Mamad once again. There was a big crowd: the king was about to go hunting. The king held his horse by the mane, his left foot was already on the stirrup. He ordered Mamad:

"Go to my summer palace and tell the queen I will be with her for lunch. Tell her to prepare a big feast. You will have lunch with me then."

Mamad bowed down and went to the queen. Then the king laughed and said:

"We won't go hunting and now Mamad will lie to the queen. Tomorrow we will laugh on his behalf."

But the wise Mamad went to the palace and said:

"Maybe you should prepare a big feast for lunch tomorrow, and maybe you shouldn't. Maybe the king will come by noon, and maybe he won't."

"Tell me will he come, or won't he?" - asked the queen.

"I don't know weather he put his right foot on the stirrup, or he put his left foot on the ground after I left."

Everybody waited for the king. He came the next day and said to the queen:

"The wise Mamad, who never lies, lied to you yesterday."

But the queen told him about the words of Mamad. And the king realized, that the wise man never lies, and says only that, which he saw with his own eyes.</string>
    <string name="cindrela">Cinderella</string>
    <string name="cindrelaplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="cindrelastop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="cindrelacontent">ONCE UPON A TIME a girl named Cinderella lived with her stepmother and two stepsisters.  Poor Cinderella had to work hard all day long so the others could rest. It was she who had to wake up each morning when it was still dark and cold to start the fire.  It was she who cooked the meals. It was she who kept the fire going. The poor girl could not stay clean, from all the ashes and cinders by the fire.

 Cinderella Story
Thank you, Artist Carla Oly



“What a mess!” her two stepsisters laughed.  And that is why they called her “Cinderella.”

One day, big news came to town.  The King and Queen were going to have a ball!  It was time for the Prince to find a bride. All of the young ladies in the land were invited to come.  They were wild with joy! They would wear their most beautiful gown and fix their hair extra nice. Maybe the prince would like them!

At Cinderella’s house, she now had extra work to do.  She had to make two brand-new gowns for her step-sisters.

“Faster!” shouted one step-sister.

“You call that a dress?” screamed the other.

“Oh, dear!” said Cinderella.  “When can I–“

The stepmother marched into the room.  “When can you WHAT?”

“Well,” said the girl, “when will I have time to make my own dress for the ball?”

“You?” yelled the stepmother.  “Who said YOU were going to the ball?”

“What a laugh!” said one step-sister.

“Such a mess!” They pointed at Cinderella.  All of them laughed.

Cinderella said to herself, “When they look at me, maybe they see a mess.  But I am not that way.  And if I could, I WOULD go to the ball.”

Soon the time came for the stepmother and step-sisters to leave for the big party.

 Cinderella Story
Thank you, Artist Carla Oly

Their fine carriage came to the door. The stepmother and step-sisters hopped inside.  And they were off.

“Good-bye!” called Cinderella.  “Have a good time!” But her stepmother and step-sisters did not turn around to see her.

“Ah, me!” said Cinderella sadly.  The carriage rode down the street.  She said aloud, “I wish I could go to the ball, too!”

Then - Poof!

All of a sudden, in front of her was a fairy.

“You called?” said the fairy.

“Did I?” said Cinderella.  “Who are you?”

“Why, your Fairy Godmother, of course!  I know your wish.  And I have come to grant it.”

“But…” said Cinderella, “my wish is impossible.”

“Excuse me!” said the Fairy Godmother in a huff.  “Did I not just show up out of thin air?”

“Yes, you did,” said Cinderella.

“Then let me be the one to say what is possible or not!”

“Well, I think you know I want to go to the ball, too.” She looked down at her dirty clothes.

 “But look at me.”

“You do look a bit of a mess, child,” said the Fairy Godmother.

“Even if I had something nice to wear," said the girl, "I would have no way to get there."

“Dear me, all of that is possible,” said the Fairy. With that, she tapped her wand on Cinderella’s head.

</string>
    <string name="hansel">Hansel and Gretel</string>
    <string name="hanselplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="hanselstop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="hanselcontent">A poor woodcutter and his wife had two children named Hansel and Gretel. Their mother died when they were young. Hansel and Gretel were very sad. Soon their father remarried but their stepmother was very cruel. One day, she took the children deep into the forest and left them there. Clever Hansel had some breadcrumbs in his pocket and had dropped them on the way so that they could find their way back home. Alas! The birds ate all the crumbs and they couldn’t find the path that led back home.

Hansel and Gretel went deeper and deeper into the forest. They were hungry and tired. Finally, after walking for a long time, they saw a cottage made of chocolate, candies, and cake. “Look, Hansel! A chocolate brick!” shouted

Gretel in delight and both ate it hungrily.
        Now, a wicked witch lived there. When she saw Hansel and Gretel, she wanted to eat them. She grabbed the children and locked them in a cage. The witch decided to make a soup out of Hansel and eat him first. She began boiling a huge pot of water for the soup. Just then, Gretel crept out of her cage. She gave the wicked witch a mighty push from behind and the witch fell into the boiling water. She howled in pain and died instantly. Hansel and Gretel found treasure lying around the cottage. They carried it home with them. Their stepmother had died and their father welcomed them back with tears of joy. They never went hungry again!
    </string>
    <string name="ugly">The Ugly Duckling</string>
    <string name="uglyplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="uglystop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="uglycontent">The story tells of a plain-looking little bird (the Ugly Duckling) born in a barnyard. His brothers and sisters as well as the other birds and animals on the farm tease him for being plain and ugly, so he runs off to live with a flock of wild ducks and geese until hunters shoot down the flock. Alone again, the Ugly Duckling finds a home with an old woman, but her cat and hen also tease him, so he does not stay there longIn his wanderings, the Ugly Duckling comes across a flock of migrating swans, and he wishes to join them but can not because he is too young and can not fly well enough. When winter sets in, a farmer rescues the Ugly Duckling, but the farmers children and other animals frighten him with their noise and teasing, so again, he flees. He spends a cold and lonely winter hiding in a cave until springtime, when the flock of swans comes to the lake near his hiding place.When the Ugly Duckling approaches the swans, he is delighted to find that they accept him and treat him like one of them. When he looks at his reflection in the lake, he realizes, to his astonishment, that he is matured into a beautiful swan himself. When the swans fly off from the lake, he spreads his wings and joins them, finally having found a family who accepts him.</string>
    <string name="bambi">Bambi Story</string>
    <string name="bambiplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="bambistop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="bambicontent">It is spring, and all the animals of the forest are excited by the forest s latest birth, a buck fawn his mother has named Bambi. The animals are more excited than usual as Bambis lineage means he will inherit the title of prince of the forest. Along with his mother, Bambi navigates through life with the help of his similarly aged friends, Thumper, a rabbit kit who needs to be continually reminded by his mother of all the lessons his father has taught him about how to live as a rabbit properly, and Flower, a skunk kit who likes his name. As different animals, they have their own issues and challenges which may not translate to the others. Being similarly aged, Bambi, Thumper and Flower may have to experience the uncharted phases of their lives without the knowledge or wisdom unless gleaned from those who have gone through them before. Bambi has to learn early that the lives of deer and of many of the other forest animals are not without their inherent dangers, for deer especially in the beautiful albeit exposed meadow. Bambi will also find that his ascension to prince of the forest is not a guarantee as other buck deer and situations may threaten that ascension.
</string>
    <string name="stone">The Sword in the stone</string>
    <string name="stoneplay"> ▶️</string>
    <string name="stonestop"> ⏹️</string>
    <string name="stonecontent">The Sword in the Stone, a King Arthur Legend of the Sword Story ~ Legends Stories for Kids
This is the Tale of The Sword in the Stone, a King Arthur Legend of the Sword Story. It is one of the many tales of King Arthur and the Knights of the Round Table.It is adapted and brought to you by Stories to Grow by.Long ago in England, a wise and just king ruled the land.  His name was King Uther. Times were good and the people lived well.  King Uther wanted a magician at court. And so he chose the famous Merlin the Magician.  Merlin could see into the future. And he knew those good days were not going to last.King Uther and the Queen Guinevere had a child, a baby son.  At a castle party for the royal birth, Merlin the Magician took the King aside.  He said, “Sire, there is something you must know. Soon a great darkness will fall over this land.  Your child is in great danger. Let me take the baby far away. I will be sure he stays safe.”“Merlin!” said the King in surprise. “You are a great magician.  And you are my friend. But there is no way we would let anyone take our child away!”</string>

</resources>